Daniel Pathammavong

Fullstack Software Engineer

6124180629
patha037@umn.edu
www.linkedin.com/in/danielpatha/
Minneapolis, Minnesota

SUMMARY

A creative and analytical full stack software engineer, leveraging various past experiences to the tech field as I create and manage full stack web applications. I approach projects with a client and usability focus, using technologies like JavaScript, React, Redux, Saga, and SQL.

EXPERIENCE

08/2022 - Present

Software Engineer Student

Prime Digital Academy

Solo Project: MinneLeagues

- MinneLeagues is a web application that allows users to search adult rec leagues across the Twin-Cities and beyond all in one place, which streamlines the process.
- Technologies Used: JavaScript, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, SQL, Redux-Saga, and Figma.

Group Client Project: Faceless Pro (In Dev)

Faceless Pro is a web application offering users the ability to apply for jobs incognito, forgoing
specific information in the application process to prevent unconscious bias or discrimination in the
hiring process.

01/2019 - 07/2022

Freelance Videographer

Freelance

- Executed all video production planning, shot lists, camera operation, shooting, editing and publishing
- Routinely exceeded client expectations and deadlines by demonstrating a continued willingness to improve
- Coordinated with key organization members and clients on video content structure, schedule, and details
- Deployed a level-headed focus and patience to projects and an adaptable approach to inevitable changes in production

01/2021 - 12/2021

Videographer

Richfield Historical Society

- Communicated effectively with board members and key partners to strategize video content development
- Planned and executed weekly video production deadlines and coordinate scheduling for social media content
- Increased social media engagement and views and successfully boosted monthly donations by over 50%
- Utilized motion graphics and theme music to help customize, redesign, and improve the brand identity

EDUCATION

2023 Fullstack Software Engineering

Prime Digital Academy

Full Stack Software Engineering Certification

- Hands-on learning using various languages and technologies with an engineering instructor in a real-world setting
- · Develop full stack web applications individually and with cohort peers
- · Attend professional networking events and mentorship meetings

2020 Family Social Science

University of Minnesota Twin-Cities

Bachelor's of Science

CEHD Global Discovery Scholarship 2019

Dean's List Fall 2017

SKILLS

JavaScript Figma

Express.js Software Testing & Debugging

jQuery Time-Management

C# Creative Problem-Solving

React.js Written/Verbal Communication

Node.js Team Collaboration

SQL

Redux-Saga

LANGUAGES

English Laotian